# Raymond Harvey, IT Specialist

2137068506, harveyraymondc@gmail.com

P	R	O	F	I	L	E

Dependable and Customer Focused IT Specialist with 5+ years of Customer Service experience, and 2+ years of IT experience. Worked to install, and maintain computer systems for various clients. Solid experience resolving challenging technical issues in a rapid, and cost-effective manner. Solid understanding of the foundations of Networking processes. Enjoys learning new skills and information to increase my knowledge and abilities.

#### CERTIFICATIONS

Jun 2020 — Jun 2023

CompTIA A+

Jul 2020 — Jul 2023

CompTIA Network+ In Progress

#### **EDUCATION**

Jun 2019 — Jun 2021

Computer Science, Santa Monica College

Santa Monica

3.7 GPA

SKILLS

Leadership

**Technical Support** 

Software Troubleshooting

Hardware Troubleshooting

Communication Skills

Customer service

Hardware Configuration

Mac Support

TCP/IP

Networking

Operating Systems

Help Desk

Mobile Device Support

System Backup and Recovery

System Administration

Virtualization

Cybersecurity

#### IT WORK EXPERIENCE

Sep 2010 — Sep 2011

### Customer Service/Technical Support

Christiansburg

- Customer Care Specialist responsible for assisting customers on a wide range of topics including payments and billing, product features, sales, and technical support.
- Technical Support: Assisted customers with video playback, satellite connectivity, signal loss, remotes, hardware receivers, and physical connections. Educating the user on troubleshooting steps and ways on preventing a recurring issue.
- Payments and Billing: Accept payments by credit card, offer self-service solutions, assist with pay-per-view orders, change customer packages, assist with equipment upgrades, and answer general questions

## Nov 2017 — Present

## Independent IT Specialist

- Installing and configuring hardware and software components to ensure usability.
- Troubleshooting hardware and software issues in person, remotely, and via phone.
- Ensuring electrical safety standards are met.
- · Repairing or replacing damaged hardware.
- Upgrading the entire system to enable compatible software on all computers.
- Installing and upgrading anti-virus software to ensure security at the user level.
- Performing tests and evaluations of new software and hardware.
- Establishing good relationships with all clients.
- · Conducting backup operations.
- Managing technical documentation.
- Travel to client sites.
- Verify the functionality of hardware and software components.
- Set up workstations with computers and necessary peripheral devices.
- Develop and maintain SOHO networks in ways that optimize performance

- Ensure security and privacy of networks and computer systems
- · Provide orientation and guidance to users on how to operate new software and computer equipment

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Nov 2018 — Jan 2020

## Guest Service Representative, USC

Los Angeles

- Provide customer services to faculty, staff, students, and guests.
- Meet and greet guests.
- Being a source of information to guests on various matters such as transport and restaurant advice.
- Processing meal and beverage requests.
- Accommodating general and unique requests.
- Diffusing conflict or tense situations with guests.

Sep 2013 — Jun 2018

## Web Search Analyst, Independent Contractor - Leapforce

Remote

- Analyze a variety of web search engines including Google, Bing, and Yahoo
- Create qualitative data and measurements to determine the relevance of the results
- Serve as an expert on web search, video, and digital search trends
- · Determine the relevance, quality and usefulness of search engine results
- Use qualitative data to provide recommendations on optimizing search engine results
- Work independently and on a team, depending on the project, to enhance search engine results
- Present evaluation findings to the department along with recommendations and solutions
- Multitask on multiple evaluation projects'

LANGUAGES

English

Native speaker

### EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Feb 2018 — Present

# Independent Video Game Developer

- Develop and maintain codes for game programs.
- Perform debugging and troubleshooting of game applications.
- Document design specifications to support the development of the game application.
- Ensure that the game application meets functional and performance requirements.
- · Work with artists to implement new features and identify and fix bugs
- Develop high-quality game systems and software
- · Composing, recording, and performing musical scores and arrangements
- Collaborates effectively with the development team as well as an operating team
- Provides technical leadership and assumes overall accountability for a successful implementation phase on all feature releases and builds
- Use computers and synthesizers to compose, orchestrate, and arrange music.